Bartosz Kraszewski +48 506251075 bkraszewski@gmail.com

Sybirakow 16/35 204 Bialystok, Poland linkedin.com/in/bkraszewski

github.com/bkraszewski

Profile

Passionate mobile apps engineer open to challenges and learning new stuff.

Known for good teamwork and leadership skills. Excellent with Dart and Flutter. Has experience with native Android/iOS development - programming language is just another tool for me to achieve my goal.

Passion for designing and implementing multi-platform UX-focused solutions. Tenacious problem-solver with a strong work ethic.

Professional Experience

Klar - Senior Flutter Developer 9/2022 - now

Klar provides digital banking solutions to underbanked Mexicans typically overlooked by traditional banking systems. Democratizing access to financial products and services, Klar aims to become the financial cornerstone for its 1.2M (and growing) client base.

- Member of a Credit Cash team, responsible for File Downloader, an internal PDF browser.
- Working 100% in the TDD approach.

Publicis Sapient - Flutter Team Lead (Contract) 5/2021 - 5/2022

Worked as a contractor leading a small team for Fintech products.

- Developed a bank application with many Fintech integrations from scratch in less than one year.
- I was responsible for new user registration, onboarding, and KYB/KYC process.

Toptal.com - Flutter/Android Freelancer 9/1/2019 - now

Remote freelance developer in an exclusive network of the top 3% of talents. Projects:

- Monarch is a tool for building Flutter widgets in isolation. It makes it easy to build, test, and debug complex Uls. Written in Dart and native platform languages
- ReMojo Worked as a full-stack developer, implementing proof of concept of porn blocking app. Then, iterated and turned it into a commercial, production-ready app. The technology in use is Kotlin, Firebase, and NodeJS.
- Hypothesis worked as a full-stack developer, creating a social media app to share hypotheses and predictions. It's a Flutter app backed by Firebase and Cloud Functions.
- Worked as a full-stack developer, creating Twelve Fixes a mobile habit helper, written in Flutter, backed with Firebase and Cloud Functions

SoftwareHut.com - Android/Flutter Tech Lead 4/1/2016 - 12/1/2020

Developer with leadership responsibilities.

Kev roles:

- Working as an Android Team Leader in a distributed remote team developing complex multi-flavor fitness/personal health applications. Responsible for planning, developing, refactoring, and also mentoring team members
- Adding new features and maintaining codebase including adding Kotlin Support, introducing multi-module architecture, introducing MVP and later MVVM approach, data binding
- Project optimizations: reduced startup time and retrieved tons of lost animation frames
- Tech Lead of the Android department, responsible for recruiting, helping the sales team, estimating projects, and reviewing and mentoring team members.
- Introduced Flutter Development into the company after research, decided to bet on it and help the coaching team of Android/IOS developers. Evangelizing the sales team to promote Flutter more among customers who could benefit from it.
- Part of a Dev Speaking Team preparing presentations delivered all over Poland and Europe see https://softwarehut.com/speaking/

Mewe.com - Senior Android Developer 6/1/2015 - 2/1/2016

Constantly improving privacy by design social network app.

Working on the native Android app, implementing new features, and maintaining the current codebase. Member of a distributed team working remotely.

Key roles:

- Mainly responsible for albums and photo-related features.
- Responsible for reskinning and optimizing authorization pages
- Implemented a lot of features related to public/private groups

Chemik.IO Startup - Co-Founder and Lead Developer in side-startup 1/02/2013 - 2016

- Multi-platform architecture design (SQLite) Created native Android and iOS app (Java, Objective C),
- Also developed a bunch of utility software to manage database improvement (JavaFX and NodeJS)
- Reached over 250k installs, the experience of owning app development me both as a software engineer and business person

TangramCare - Software Engineer / Team Leader 8/1/2013 - 6/1/2015

Working on multiple prototypes in a fast-changing, customer-oriented environment. Implementing mobile, web, and cloud apps for health care. Requirements analysis, conducting meetings with the UX/Marketing team from the USA. Leader role in agile software team (4 - 10 developers), scrum master Projects:

- TangramSafe Kiosk app for tablets a secure platform for performing patient screening. Integrated connectivity and security systems. Native Android application.
- Tangram Clock Native Android app for cognitive impairment screening
- Webscreeners Set of behavioral screenings to be run on TangramSafe or a browser. Web application (Spring, GWT, Postgresql, MongoDB)
- Annual Wellness Visit Web application for managing annual doctor appointments for elder folks. (Spring, GWT, Postgresql, MongoDB)

Tower Group - Database developer 6/1/2012 - 8/1/2013

Offshore team member in the Enterprise data warehouse project: www.twrgrp.com

Microsoft SQL Server technology - T-SQL programming, Integration Services, Reporting Services.

Experience in the ETL process, working with large data sets, conversion, and integration between financial systems.

GRC Solutions grcsolutions.pl – Junior Java developer 3/1/2011 – 5/15/2012

Working as a junior full-stack developer. Using Java EE and Javascript - JSF framework, jQuery, Microsoft SQL Server 2008 – T-SQL programming, database design. Responsible for unit and integration testing of various modules.

Education

Bialystok Technical University

2008 - 2014

Master's Degree in Computer Science. Specialization in Software Engineering. MA Thesis – Supervised classification of biomedical data.

Bachelor's Degree in Computer Science.

Online courses (Coursera.com)

Algorithms, Social Computing, Fundamentals of management, Smartphones emerging technologies, Developing Innovative Ideas for New Companies, Innovation for Entrepreneurs: From Idea to Marketplace

Useful Skills

Android: Java/Kotlin, multi-module, rxJava2, unit testing, mockito, jUnit, MVP/MVVM, clean architecture, dagger, room, data binding, and other as long as I can access documentation:)

Flutter: Dart, streams, state management, native channel integration, rxDart, mocktail,

Web: Javascript, nodejs, angularJS, html, css

Public Speaking experience

I attended a few conferences speaking as an Android Expert: See the complete listing on my LinkedIn profile, below featured:

Monarch - The Royal Way to develop your widgets in isolation

Oct. 28, 2021, Droidcon London

Becoming a full-stack superhero with Flutter and Firebase

Sep 22, 2020, Webinar for Droidcon Italy

Tensorflow and ML Kit for Android Developers

Dec 11, 2018, Mobile Białystok

Your phone is learning! Introduction to running Tensorflow on Android

Sep 21, 2018, Droidcon Vienna

Optimizing Android application performance with AT&T Video Optimizer

Dec 1, 2017, Droidcon Kraków 2017

Who am I as a person?

I'm interested in sports - I am an amateur squash player and a CrossFit athlete. My interests are business - startup ecosystem and the stock market - investing and psychology of trading.

I hereby give consent for my personal data included in my application to be processed for the purposes of the recruitment process under the European Parliament and the Council of the European Union Regulation on the Protection of Natural Persons as of 27 April 2016, with regard to the processing of personal data and on the free movement of such data, and repealing Directive 95/46/EC (Data Protection Directive)